SAMIL ABUD

CERTIFIED FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

+1829-303-0147 | DOMINICAN REPUBLIC | SAMILABUD@GMAIL.COM

Objective

Experienced full-stack web developer with a proven track record of delivering high-quality web applications. Seeking a challenging role to leverage my expertise in JavaScript, React, Node.js, and database management to drive innovation and create exceptional user experiences for clients and end-users.

Skills & abilities

Ability to identify and resolve complex technical issues efficiently. Effective communication skills, for collaborating with team members and stakeholders. Organizing and prioritizing tasks to meet project deadlines. Proficient in a range of programming languages, with experience in developing and maintaining responsive, user-friendly, and visually appealing websites.

Experience

BAIRESDEV | PINTEREST (US)

Full-stack Web Developer (remote) | October 2021 - Current

- Developed audience sharing module for Pinterest's Advertiser
 Automation web system which increased advertiser campaign creation by
 30% more, with this feature advertisers could share custom audience
 between campaigns and accounts with this we received over 90% good
 feedback from users/advertisers.
- Ensured seamless cross-browser compatibility and responsive design, resulting in a consistent user experience across all devices and browsers.

Tech Stack: React, RTL, Redux, Cypress, Python, MySQL, Figma, Git, Flow, JSX, JavaScript, Gestalt, AWS, Jenkins.

BANCO BHD (DR)

Team Leader Full-stack (hybrid) | December 2011 – October 2021

- Design and implement internal solutions to financial and laundry department, main tasks executed in the project:
 - Resolved 20 critical and 132 non-critical bugs, ensuring a smooth user experience and maintaining a low bug count during the last 2 years working for the team.
 - Achieved a client satisfaction rating of 65% based on feedback surveys, demonstrating excellent communication skills and the ability to meet client expectations.
- Led a team of 4 in the successful delivery of implementation of anti-money laundering prevention system, demonstrating strong leadership and project management skills.

Tech Stack: C#, .Net Framework, .Net Core, SQL Server, Oracle, React, NodeJS, Git, DevOps, Azure.

Education

UNAPEC UNIVERSITY

Santo Domingo, DR | Systems Engineering | Graduation date 2012

Leadership Mentor junior developers, coordinate project tasks, and implement best practices to ensure timely delivery of high-quality web applications. Certifications 2022-05 Complete React Native in 2022: Zero to Mastery (with Hooks) 2021-08 Complete React Developer in 2021 (w/ Redux, Hooks, GraphQL) 2020-06 The Complete Web Developer in 2020 2019-01 Scrum Master Certification 2018-03 CSS Fundamentals, SQL Fundamentals, HTML Fundamentals, JavaScript Course (SoloLearn Academy) **Skills** Front-end Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Flow, React, Redux, jQuery, Tailwind, React JS, React Hooks, Redux, React Native, JSX. Back-end Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, SQL, RESTful APIs, Python, Django. Version Control: Git, GitHub Database Management: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, Oracle **Deployment and Hosting:** AWS, Heroku, Netlify, Digital Ocean Tools: Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text, Postman, Figma Project Management: Agile/Scrum, Jira **Testing:** Jest, RTL, Cypress, Enzyme Languages **Spanish:** Native English: Advanced C1 Portfolio GitHub: https://github.com/samilabud LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/samil-abud/ Portfolio: https://samilabud.netlify.app/ References Available upon request.